MIKAZUKI TEMPLE
(三日月寺)
Yuzuki.
結月姐
I'm back.
我們回來了
Yuzuki, Akagami!
結月姐 赤神
I'm back, Tsukuyo.
我們回來了 月夜
If you plan on staying out for a night, at least let us know.
你們要在外面過夜的話 好歹也跟我說一聲嘛
Sorry, my phone died.
抱歉哦 我手機沒電了
But it's okay. Looks like nothing unusual happened.
總之真是太好了 你們之間看起來好像也沒發生什麼事
Yes, nothing happened at all.
是的 我們之間什麼事都沒有
Something definitely happened!
你們之間到底發生了什麼
WORLDLY DESIRES
(世俗雜念)
(TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-)
《妙廟美少女》
(Episode 5: How Will You Take Responsibility?)
(第五話 你該怎樣負起責任來呢)
Goodbye!
一路順風
So you missed the last bus yesterday,
也就是說 你們昨天是因為錯過了末班車
went to a love hotel, but nothing happened?
所以才去了愛情旅館 但你們之間什麼事都沒發生囉
Yeah! We just slept there!
嗯嗯 我們就只是住了一晚
Really?
什麼嘛
I thought you had an affair on the day of your engagement.
我還以為妳訂婚當天就出軌了呢
Did you think it this way?
原來妳是這麼想的嗎
But Yuzuki,
但是 結月姐
you absolutely cannot tell anyone at school
妳在學校可千萬不能說
that Akagami is living with us.
赤神跟我們住在一起啊
Eh? But isn't it common for a temple attendant to live in the temple?
咦 但是寺務員 住在寺廟裡不是很正常嗎
It is a nunnery, Yuzuki.
我們可是尼姑庵啊結月姐
Is it necessary to be so cautious?
有必要那麼在意嗎
Of course! Living with a young man
那當然 和年輕男性同居這種事
would harm our reputation…
可是會對我們的信用…
But if it's Akagami, it's okay, right?
但是 如果是赤神的話應該沒關係吧
-We went to a love hotel and nothing… -Yuzuki!
-都去愛情旅館了他也什麼都沒… -結月姐
Anyway!
總之
The fact that Akagami is living with us must be kept secret!
赤神和我們住在一起這件事 絕對要保密
Understood?
妳明白了嗎
Gosh, Yuzuki really has no vigilance at all.
真是的 結月姐的警覺性還真低啊
Before Akagami came, she was more…
在赤神來我們家之前 她明明更…
She was more…
之前她明明更…
Tsuki.
小月
Morning.
早呀
Mana, Yuki, good morning.
麻奈 祐希 早安
What's up? You look a bit down.
怎麼啦 妳看起來沒什麼精神耶
Ah, it's just something at home.
哎呀 都是我家裡的事啦
Something at the temple?
寺廟的事嗎
Right, speaking of the temple,
對了 說到寺廟的話
I heard you have a boyfriend?
我們聽說小月妳有男友了喔
What are you talking about?
你們在說什麼啊
I don't!
而且我又沒有男友
Somebody saw you.
有人親眼看到了哦
Saw me?
什麼親眼看到
They saw you kissing a man by the river after the rain.
那個人說妳在雨後的河畔和男人親親
And then you went home together!
然後你們就這樣一起回去了
That must be someone else.
那肯定是認錯人了吧
But that man was wearing a monk's robe.
但是我聽說那個男的穿的是袈裟耶
A monk's robe?
穿袈裟…
Was it then?
原來是那時候嗎
No!
那個不是啦
And it wasn't just the two of us! Yuzuki was there too!
而且也不是只有我們兩個人 當時結月姐也在呢
Oh, in front of your sister!
哎呀 妳竟然當著姐姐的面…
I told you it wasn't like that!
我都說了不是了
-We were just whispering! -Whispering?
-那時我只是在跟他說悄悄話啦 -悄悄話嗎
Yes! And the kiss…
沒錯 就是之前我跟他接吻…
You did kiss after all!
妳果然有跟他親親嘛
-Then he is your boyfriend. -Tell us more about it.
-那就確定是妳的男友啦 -妳再說詳細一點嘛
No!
不是 不是啦
-This is quite an event. -Yes, it is.
-這可真是個大事件呢 -對呀
You are the target of many boys.
想追妳的男生可不少哦
What?
什麼
Although you don't realize it,
雖然妳自己沒有察覺
the Aoba sisters are quite popular in school.
但你們蒼葉姐妹 在學校裡可是很有人氣的呢
Your sister Yuzuki is famous for her beauty.
姐姐結月因為容貌出眾所以很有名
And you…
妳嘛
-You are big. -Huge.
-就是很大 -巨大
What are you saying?
你們在說什麼啦
The news that you have a boyfriend
小月 妳有男友這件事
is now all the rage.
現在可是傳得沸沸揚揚的哦
Ah…
什麼…
Tell us about it!
妳就講給我們聽嘛
-Tell us about it. -That's not good.
-妳就講給我們聽嘛 -不好
If they know that I'm living with him,
萬一讓她們知道我們和那傢伙
it's all over…
住在一起 那就完…
What's wrong?
妳怎麼了
-He came to school? -How vigilant.
-那傢伙怎麼會在學校啊 -動作好快
And he's wearing a monk's robe.
好死不死 他居然還穿著袈裟
TSUKUYO'S LUNCH
(月夜的便當)
I was so careless?
是我忘記拿了嗎
I'm going to the infirmary!
我去一下保健室
-The infirmary? -And she's sprinting.
-妳為什麼要去保健室 -而且她還是全力衝刺
Excuse me, which class is Aoba Tsukuyo in?
請問蒼葉月夜是哪一班的
The Aoba sisters…
蒼葉妹妹的話…
Wait, who are you?
話說你是什麼人啊
Sorry, I didn't introduce myself.
失禮了
I'm here to deliver lunch to Tsukuyo.
我是來給月夜送便當的
Akagami…
赤神…
Where am I?
我 我在哪
You're awake?
你醒啦
Shh, it's me!
噓 是我啦是我
Tsukuyo? What is this…
月夜 這裡是…
The infirmary.
保健室
The teacher hasn't arrived at this time.
現在這個時間老師還沒來
You forgot your lunch box.
對了 妳忘記帶便當了
Well… Even though I want to thank you…
那個…雖然我很想謝謝你 但是…
I've completed my task. See you.
那我就此告辭啦
Wait! Gym class is about to begin!
等一下等一下 外面要上體育課了
You will be seen!
你會被人看見的
Is there any problem?
這有什麼問題嗎
There're many problems!
問題可大了
You wearing a monk's robe is too conspicuous!
你穿袈裟太顯眼了
I don't think a person wearing a monk's robe in school would be considered suspicious.
我覺得穿袈裟來學校 應該不至於會被懷疑吧
This depends on the timing and location, Akagami.
這個是看時間跟場合啊 赤神
Anyway, you hide here for now.
總之你就先在這裡躲一下
No way! The teacher is here?
不會吧 老師已經來了嗎
1-B KANNA, 1-B GEKKA
(1-B神奈 1-B月下)
Excuse us.
打擾囉
Tsuki, are you there?
小月妳在嗎
Hello.
嗨
How do you feel?
妳的身體怎麼樣了
I lied down for a while and feel fine now.
我只要躺一下就會沒事了
Not fine at all!
這真的無問題嗎
Why did you come over?
你們兩個怎麼過來了
Next is gym class, we just came by to check on you.
下一節課是體育課 所以我們就順便來看看妳了
Really? Thanks. I'm fine now. Don't worry.
這樣啊 謝謝你們 不用擔心 我已經沒事了
Hey, Tsuki.
對了 小月
Why do your legs look so long?
妳的腿怎麼看起來這麼長
Not good! I have to shrink into the blanket a bit more…
不好 我得鑽進被子調整一下…
Not good! I have to move up a bit…
不妙 我得再往上移動一點…
What's wrong?
妳怎麼了
Leg… leg cramp.
腳…我的腳抽筋了
Oh, a cramp.
是腳啊
Yes! It's not a big deal.
嗯 我沒什麼大礙啦
If I don't mind this guy getting in my clothes…
除了這傢伙鑽進了我的衣服以外…
The break is about to end.
下課時間馬上就要結束了
You should go to class.
你們也快點去上課吧
Yeah, we should go.
是呀 我們也該走了
Hey, Tsuki, did you get fat?
對了 小月 妳是不是變胖啦
It must be your imagination.
是妳的錯覺啦
I didn't get fat at all!
我才沒有變胖咧
She's gonna cry!
妳怎麼激動到哭了
-Please go, please. -Sorry.
-拜託你們快點走吧 -抱歉抱歉
I'm suffocating.
好難受
If I don't breathe…
再不喘氣我就…
What…
這 這傢伙
What did he do?
到底在幹什麼啊
Tsuki, listen to me.
小月 那個呀
You're still not going back to the archery club?
妳還是不打算回弓道社嗎
The competition is coming soon.
而且比賽也快到了
Everyone misses you.
大家都很想妳耶
Sorry, I'm really busy at home.
抱歉 我家裡實在是太忙了
Ah, you still can't?
這樣啊 果然還是不行嗎
-I'm really sorry. -It's okay. We don't want to force you.
-真的很抱歉 -沒事啦 妳不用勉強
Well, we'll go now.
那我們就走囉
It's… it's like nirvana…
我…我彷彿經歷了涅槃…
This guy took advantage of me.
這傢伙 竟然給我趁火打劫
Tsukuyo, you used to be in the archery club?
月夜 原來妳以前是弓道社的啊
Well… 'used to' is not accurate.
嗯…也不算以前吧
You're not planning to continue?
妳已經不打算繼續了嗎
Right now, I'm… taking a break…
我目前…在暫停活動中…
I see. Then let's go through the procedures to resume it.
原來是這樣啊 那麼妳就快去辦恢復活動的手續吧
Eh…wait…
咦…等等…
It's okay. Leave the work at home to me!
沒事 家裡的工作就交給我吧
Wait a minute, Akagami!
等一下 赤神
1-B KANNA, 1-B GEKKA Tsuki, the class after gym is changed into self-study.
(1-B神奈 1-B月下) 小月 體育課之後的那節課改成自習…
THE NARROW DOOR IS HARD TO ENTER (TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-)
(窄門難進) (妙廟美少女)
I used to admire her posture in archery,
我曾十分憧憬她拉弓的姿勢
and that dignified face.
以及那凜然的側臉
CLUB ENTRY APPLICATION FROM 1-B AOBA TSUKUYO I want to get closer to her, even just a little bit.
(社團入社申請 希望加入弓道社 學生姓名 1-B蒼葉月夜) 就算只是一點點也好 我也想接近她
But…
但是
Eh, you are going to quit the archery club?
咦 結月姐 妳要退出弓道社嗎
Why?
為什麼
I plan to… inherit this temple.
我打算…繼承這所寺廟
Why is that…
怎麼這樣…
Why do I still have this dream?
為什麼我現在還會做這種夢啊
You worked hard, Akagami.
辛苦了 赤神
Good morning.
早安
Eh, is that a bow?
咦 那是弓嗎
Yes, archery is also called standing Zen.
嗯 弓道也被稱作為立禪呢
STANDING ZEN I heard that Buddhist colleges offer related courses.
(立禪) 我聽說佛教學校也會開這種課哦
-Would you like to try, Akagami? -I would love to!
-你也想試試看嗎 -當然
Tsukuyo is in the archery club, right?
對了 月夜是弓道社的 對吧
Yes, but she quit.
對呀 不過她已經退出了
That's a pity.
真是可惜呀
Quit?
她退出了…
I remember Tsukuyo said…
我記得月夜說的是…
Tsukuyo?
月夜
She won't open the door.
她不會開門的哦
She's in hermit mode right now.
她現在是閉門不出模式
Whenever Tsukuyo has something bothering her,
月夜姐姐每次有煩心事時
she'll lock herself in her room.
就會把自己關在房間裡
No problem! Leave it to me!
沒關係 交給我吧
There's no point in worrying about this now.
明明現在煩惱這個也已經無濟於事了
Right now I'm… taking a break…
我目前…在暫停活動中…
I really have a knack for giving up halfway.
我還真是容易半途而廢啊…
Tsukuyo!
月夜
Can I take a bit of your time?
我可以佔用妳一點時間嗎
I have a few words to say to you.
我有幾句話想對妳說
I'm saved.
得救了
What do you want to do?
你到底想幹什麼…
What did you want to say? Say it.
你想說什麼 快點說吧
I've already done today's cooking, washing, and cleaning.
我已經做完今天的 料理 洗滌 打掃了
I've also checked last month's accounts.
上個月的帳目我也都對完了
I can handle hosting and answering the phone by myself.
待客和接電話我一個人也能完成
Thank you.
謝謝你呀
So, Tsukuyo!
所以說 月夜
You can return to the archery club without any worries.
就算妳現在要回弓道社也沒關係
-You should do it today… -Listen, Akagami.
-不然妳今天就… -我說啊 赤神
You seem to have misunderstood something since yesterday.
你好像從昨天開始就誤會了些什麼啊
I don't really want to practice archery.
我其實對弓道並沒有很感興趣
Is that so?
是這樣嗎
Hmm.
嗯
Then why are you still on hiatus
那為什麼妳到現在
instead of just quitting?
都還沒有退出 而是一直暫停活動呢
It seems like you're preparing to return at any time.
妳不是為了隨時都能回去嗎
I feel a bit breathless. I'll go out for a walk.
總覺得有點喘不過氣 我要出去走走
I'll leave the rest of the work to you, Akagami.
剩下的工作就拜託你了 赤神
Akagami…
赤神那傢伙真是的
He's always meddling in other people's business.
總是多管閒事
What should I do after this?
接下來該怎麼才好呢
-Over here. -Wait for me.
-這裡這裡 -等等我
Oh my, how did I end up here?
哎呀 我怎麼走到這裡來了
Oh gosh, they are organizing this place so carelessly.
真是的 他們居然整理的這麼隨便
This bowstring is tied so badly.
這弓弦也綁的太爛了吧
Draw.
架弓
Release.
放箭
What am I doing?
我在幹什麼呀
Bullseye!
正中靶心
Akagami? Why are you here?
赤神 你為什麼會在這
Damn!
糟糕
Tsukuyo?
月夜
Why are you running away?
妳為什麼要逃走
Nothing.
沒什麼
I just don't want others to see me with you.
我只是不想讓別人看到 我和你在一起而已
Have you made up your mind to return to the archery club?
妳果然還是想回到弓道社嗎
I said that I don't want to continue.
我都說了我不會回去了
But,
但是
Tsukuyo, you look very happy
月夜妳在弓道場時
on the archery field.
看起來很開心啊
Exactly.
就是因為開心
I can't… because it just makes me happy…
就是因為只是開心…所以才不行的
I'm not particularly talented in archery.
我在弓道上也並非很有天賦
The reason I started practicing archery
我之所以開始接觸弓道
was because Yuzuki was in the archery club and I just followed her.
也只是因為之前結月姐在弓道社 所以我才跟著加入的
The person who should continue practicing archery
應該繼續練習弓道的人
shouldn't be me, but Yuzuki.
其實不應該是我 而是結月姐啊
She's more talented than me,
她比我更有天賦
and more reputable.
也更有人氣
But she quit.
但是她卻退出了
Yuzuki is forcing herself for the sake of everyone else.
結月姐明明是為了我們才勉強自己的
How can I be so selfish and do whatever I want?
我怎麼可以任性地去做 自己想做的事情啊
You should understand
你應該也能理解
the difficulties of inheriting this temple!
繼承寺廟有多辛苦吧
Sis Yuzuki is just a high school student.
結月姐明明還只是一個高中生
But she's determined to inherit the temple and go on dates.
她卻決定要繼承寺廟 而且還跑去相親
I can't do it like her.
我根本就學不來
Yuzuki is really amazing.
結月姐真的很了不起
In summary,
也就是說
you think Yuzuki quit the archery club and she's forcing herself for something,
妳以為結月不僅退出了弓道社 而且還在勉強她自己
so you can't just think about your own happiness, right?
所以妳才不想要 只有自己在開心 對吧
-I've said it several times… -Come with me.
-我都說過幾遍了 -跟我來
I have something to show you.
我有東西要給妳看
What?
什麼
Right here.
就是這裡
Isn't this our temple?
這裡不就是我家的寺廟嗎
-Yes, right behind the main hall! -Eh, wait…
-嗯 就在正殿後面 -咦 等等…
How is she…
為什麼
I want you to understand
我想讓月夜妳知道
whether Yuzuki is really just struggling in pain
結月是否真的像妳說的那樣
like you said.
只是自己一個人在痛苦
Please accept
同時我也要請妳接受
the real Yuzuki.
結月真實的樣貌
No… I don't want to see…
不要…我不想看…
Her face
她的側臉
is still the one I used to admire.
依舊是跟我過去憧憬的那樣
That's the real Yuzuki.
這就是結月真實的樣貌
The so-called talent
所謂的天賦
That's super cool!
這不是超級帥氣的嗎
I said I didn't want to see it!
哎呀 哎呀 我都說了不想看了
Akagami, you're an idiot!
赤神你這個笨蛋
After seeing it, I will want to return to the archery club!
看她那樣 會害我也想練弓道啦
Calm down, Tsukuyo.
妳冷靜一點 月夜
Did you look closely?
妳真的有仔細看嗎
What you just saw was an abled sports idiot.
妳剛剛看到的可是四肢發達 但卻是個運動白痴的奇蹟場景啊
She practiced archery for over a year, but still can't master it at all.
她連續練習了一年以上的弓道 卻還是廢到了這種地步
I'm right here, Akagami.
我有在聽喔 赤神
I told you I don't have any talent for archery.
我就說嘛… 我根本就沒有什麼弓道的天賦嘛
That's why I quit.
所以我才會退社呀
Can't be more obvious.
還真是一目瞭然呢
It's okay! Miss Yuzuki!
沒關係的 結月小姐
Your posture is very beautiful,
妳的姿勢很漂亮哦
although there's nothing else good about it.
雖然除此以外哪都不行
Mia, stop talking.
米亞 妳別再說了
Let me try again! The last time was just a warm-up!
再 再讓我試一次 我剛剛那次只是練習而已
Ah? Yuzuki's archery skills are very bad.
什麼 結月姐的弓道很爛
And she didn't quit the club because of family reasons.
退出社團也不是因為家裡的原因
Really?
真的嗎
You didn't know?
妳不知道嗎
Uh, well…
呃 也就是說
Tsukuyo is blinded by her excessive love for her big sister.
過於喜歡大姐的 月夜姐姐的眼光實在太差了呢
Kurage!
海月
What do you mean?
什麼意思
Tsukuyo loves you too much.
就是月夜姐姐太愛結月姐姐了
She enters that state as long as she sees you with a bow.
只要看到妳架弓她就會進入那種狀態
Eh, it makes me shy. Stop it.
咦咦 不要那樣說嘛 我會害羞的
Stop talking.
別說了別說了
Anyway! Sis Yuzuki!
總之 結月姐
Are you happy now?
結月姐 妳現在開心嗎
Yes! I'm happy every day.
嗯 我每天都很開心哦
The work at the temple is indeed not easy,
寺廟的工作確實是挺不容易的
but every day is very fulfilling.
但我每天都過得非常充實
I'm thinking if this is what I really want to do.
我現在才發現 原來這就是我真正想做的事
So, you should do what you want to do too, Tsukuyo.
所以妳也去做自己想做的事情吧
Don't worry about things at home.
不用再擔心家裡的事了
There's one more thing.
還有一件事…
Could you occasionally
妳能不能偶爾
teach me archery?
教我一下弓道呢
-Ahahaha! -What are you laughing at?
-啊哈哈哈 -妳幹嘛笑啦
Although I think I'm stupid,
雖然連我都覺得我自己夠蠢了
I remember a good thing.
但我還是想起了一件不錯的事
Back then, Yuzuki said it with a smile.
那時結月姐 是笑著對我說的
I plan to… inherit this temple.
我打算…繼承這所寺廟
Ah, I've sweated a lot.
啊啊 出了好多汗啊
I'll go take a shower first.
先去洗個澡吧
Sorry, I saw it again…
抱歉 我又不小心看見了…
I'm also very sorry…
我也很抱歉…
We are always so reckless.
總覺得我們兩個好像一直這麼莽撞呢
I have also done a lot of rude things to you.
我真的對妳做出了不少無禮的行為
It's okay.
沒事啦
-Hey… Akagami. -Hmm?
-那個什麼…赤神 -什麼事
I decided to return to the archery club.
我決定重回弓道社了
How should I put it… It's all thanks to you.
怎麼說呢…這都是多虧了你
Thank you.
謝謝你
Really? That's great.
是嗎 那真是太好了
Akagami,
赤神
why did you do this for me?
你為什麼要為我做這麼多
I just feel that it's not good.
我就是感覺那樣不太好
Not being able to do things you want because of family reasons.
因為家裡的事 而陷入無法做自己想做的事的情況
I also gave up a lot
我也曾因為赤神這個姓氏
because of the name Akagami.
而感到不方便 甚至還有因此而放棄的事
Is that why you came to this temple?
這和你來到這所寺廟有關係嗎
How should I put it?
怎麼說呢
I just want
總之我就是想
to make you feel happy.
讓月夜獲得幸福啊
I haven't changed my clothes yet.
我還在換衣服耶
Look, this hasn't gone down yet.
我說啊 這個還沒消失耶
The hickey you gave me in the school infirmary.
就是你在保健室給我種的草莓
How will you take responsibility this time?
這次你該怎樣負起責任呢
What should I do…
我 我該怎麼做…
How about doubling your debt?
要不要讓你的欠款翻個倍呢
Please have mercy!
還請妳手下留情
-Alright, stand still. -Yes.
-好了 你給我站好 -是
Close your eyes.
閉上…眼睛
Idiot.
笨蛋
I drew something on your forehead. Let's call it even.
我也在你額頭上畫了些東西 就當是扯平了
Get dressed quickly.
你快去把衣服穿好吧
LEWDMITSU
(色神)
I'm sorry.
抱歉了
Ah! Tsukuyo forgot to bring lunch again.
哎呀 月夜又忘記帶便當了
I have to send it to her.
我得給她送過去才行
Akagami, buy some milk on the way back.
赤神 你就順便買點東西回來吧
Understood.
收到
This is new.
這個可是新的
Tsukuyo.
月夜
You forgot your lunch.
妳忘記帶便當了
Thank you.
謝謝
-What's this? -The love lunch from your boyfriend?
-怎麼回事 -這是男友的愛心便當嗎
I said I don't have a boyfriend.
我都說了我沒男友了
He's just…
這傢伙只不過是…
my family.
只不過是我的家人罷了
-What do you mean? -Siblings?
-什麼意思 -你們是兄妹嗎
Alright, go back quickly.
好了好了 你快回去吧
Ah, okay.
啊 好的
Let's… Let's establish facts.
Let's Let's 既定事實
Indirect kiss?
間接接吻嗎
Only elementary school students care about that.
小學生才會在意那個
Let's… Let's establish facts.
Let's Let's 既定事實
Have you experienced it?
你體驗過了嗎
If you don't understand, just shut up.
不明白的話就乖乖閉嘴哦
(Next Episode: Let's Eestablish Facts!)
(下集 Let's既定事實!)